[
  {
    "id": 1601,
    "question": "abrazo",
    "questionDetails": "Creo que lo que necesitas es un abrazo.",
    "answer": "hug, embrace",
    "answerDetails": "I think what you need is a hug."
  },
  {
    "id": 1602,
    "question": "vacaciones",
    "questionDetails": "¿Qué hiciste durante tus vacaciones de verano?",
    "answer": "holiday, vacation",
    "answerDetails": "What did you do during your summer holidays?"
  },
  {
    "id": 1603,
    "question": "presión",
    "questionDetails": "Siempre me sentí bajo presión en esa empresa.",
    "answer": "pressure",
    "answerDetails": "I always felt under pressure at that company."
  },
  {
    "id": 1604,
    "question": "tele",
    "answer": "TV"
  },
  {
    "id": 1605,
    "question": "usa",
    "questionDetails": "Éste es mi figura de acción favorita. Usa rayos láser para derrotar a sus enemigos.",
    "answer": "it uses, she wears, she uses",
    "answerDetails": "This is my favorite action figure. It uses laser beams to defeat its enemies."
  },
  {
    "id": 1606,
    "question": "vos",
    "questionDetails": "Vos sois muy prudente al desconfiar de estos hombres, señor mío.",
    "answer": "thou",
    "answerDetails": "Thou art most wise to be suspicious of these men, m’lord."
  },
  {
    "id": 1607,
    "question": "regreso",
    "questionDetails": "Tras mi regreso a Nueva York, volví a trabajar de periodista.",
    "answer": "return, comeback",
    "answerDetails": "Following my return to New York, I started working as a journalist again."
  },
  {
    "id": 1608,
    "question": "tocó",
    "questionDetails": "Podemos probar a Charlotte. Tocó el bajo en una banda de Jazz.",
    "answer": "she played, he felt",
    "answerDetails": "We can audition Charlotte. She played bass in a jazz band."
  },
  {
    "id": 1609,
    "question": "aseguro",
    "questionDetails": "Le aseguro que mis intenciones son nobles.",
    "answer": "assure, swear",
    "answerDetails": "I assure you my intentions are honorable."
  },
  {
    "id": 1610,
    "question": "novios",
    "questionDetails": "Sus novios son la misma persona.",
    "answer": "boyfriends, grooms, sweethearts",
    "answerDetails": "Your boyfriends are the same person."
  },
  {
    "id": 1611,
    "question": "confía",
    "questionDetails": "Confía en él y lo necesita.",
    "answer": "relies, trust, entrusted",
    "answerDetails": "He relies on him and he needs him."
  },
  {
    "id": 1612,
    "question": "cansada",
    "questionDetails": "Estoy cansada de mentir.",
    "answer": "tired, weary, sick",
    "answerDetails": "I was tired of lying."
  },
  {
    "id": 1613,
    "question": "detalles",
    "questionDetails": "Haz clic en el siguiente enlace para obtener más detalles sobre el programa del Congreso.",
    "answer": "specifics",
    "answerDetails": "Click on the following link to learn more about the specifics of the conference program."
  },
  {
    "id": 1614,
    "question": "actitud",
    "questionDetails": "No me gusta tu actitud.",
    "answer": "attitude",
    "answerDetails": "I don’t like your attitude."
  },
  {
    "id": 1615,
    "question": "río",
    "questionDetails": "Un río de sangre.",
    "answer": "river",
    "answerDetails": "A river of blood."
  },
  {
    "id": 1616,
    "question": "tonta",
    "questionDetails": "¡ Solo estaba bromeando, tonta!.",
    "answer": "silly, fool",
    "answerDetails": "I was just joking, silly!."
  },
  {
    "id": 1617,
    "question": "ayudando",
    "questionDetails": "Creía que te estábamos ayudando.",
    "answer": "helping, assisting, aiding",
    "answerDetails": "We thought we were helping."
  },
  {
    "id": 1618,
    "question": "datos",
    "questionDetails": "No hay datos suficientes para reconstruir tal objeto.",
    "answer": "data",
    "answerDetails": "Insufficient data to reconstruct the requested object."
  },
  {
    "id": 1619,
    "question": "carne",
    "questionDetails": "Nunca he sido uno para negar los placeres de la carne.",
    "answer": "flesh",
    "answerDetails": "I have never been one to deny the pleasures of the flesh."
  },
  {
    "id": 1620,
    "question": "aguantar",
    "questionDetails": "Si no puede aguantar el dolor, podemos darle anestesia.",
    "answer": "endure",
    "answerDetails": "If you cannot endure the pain, we can give you an anesthetic."
  },
  {
    "id": 1621,
    "question": "cuida",
    "questionDetails": "Su padre grita a usted porque él cuida.",
    "answer": "cares, takes care, take care",
    "answerDetails": "Your father yells at you because he cares."
  },
  {
    "id": 1622,
    "question": "azul",
    "questionDetails": "Este trozo azul, es la parte letal.",
    "answer": "blue",
    "answerDetails": "This blue portion, that’s the deadly part."
  },
  {
    "id": 1623,
    "question": "inglés",
    "questionDetails": "El inglés no es un idioma fácil de aprender.",
    "answer": "english",
    "answerDetails": "English is not an easy language to learn."
  },
  {
    "id": 1624,
    "question": "ello",
    "questionDetails": "Nunca podría hablar de ello.",
    "answer": "it",
    "answerDetails": "She would never be able to talk about it."
  },
  {
    "id": 1625,
    "question": "decirlo",
    "questionDetails": "Yo sé qué fue lo que sucedió, pero temo decirlo.",
    "answer": "say it",
    "answerDetails": "I know what happened, but I am afraid to say it."
  },
  {
    "id": 1626,
    "question": "llamamos",
    "questionDetails": "Te llamamos 3 veces pero nunca contéstaste el teléfono.",
    "answer": "we called",
    "answerDetails": "We called you three times but you never answered the phone."
  },
  {
    "id": 1627,
    "question": "déjeme",
    "questionDetails": "Sea amable y déjeme echarle un vistazo.",
    "answer": "let me",
    "answerDetails": "Do me a favour, let me take a look."
  },
  {
    "id": 1628,
    "question": "mentiras",
    "questionDetails": "Diles algunas mentiras sobre mi ahora.",
    "answer": "lies",
    "answerDetails": "Tell some lies about me now."
  },
  {
    "id": 1629,
    "question": "cantar",
    "questionDetails": "La poesía debe cantar la variedad de la raza humana.",
    "answer": "sing",
    "answerDetails": "Poetry should sing the variety of the human race."
  },
  {
    "id": 1630,
    "question": "juntas",
    "questionDetails": "Juntas hemos superado la norma.",
    "answer": "together, joints, gaskets",
    "answerDetails": "Together we exceeded the norm."
  },
  {
    "id": 1631,
    "question": "olvide",
    "answer": "Forget"
  },
  {
    "id": 1632,
    "question": "ayudarte",
    "questionDetails": "Lo siento, pero no creo que pueda ayudarte con eso.",
    "answer": "help you",
    "answerDetails": "Sorry, but I don’t think I can help you with that."
  },
  {
    "id": 1633,
    "question": "ocupado",
    "questionDetails": "Ojalá tuviera más tiempo para hablar, pero estoy muy ocupado planificando la conferencia.",
    "answer": "occupied",
    "answerDetails": "I wish I had more time to talk, but I am very occupied with planning the conference."
  },
  {
    "id": 1634,
    "question": "banda",
    "questionDetails": "No encuentro la banda de frecuencia.",
    "answer": "band, belt",
    "answerDetails": "I can’t find the frequency band."
  },
  {
    "id": 1635,
    "question": "preguntando",
    "questionDetails": "Hay gente preguntando por ti.",
    "answer": "asking, wondering, inquiring",
    "answerDetails": "People are asking for you."
  },
  {
    "id": 1636,
    "question": "acompaño",
    "questionDetails": "¿Te acompaño como segundo?",
    "answer": "accompany",
    "answerDetails": "Shall I accompany as your second?"
  },
  {
    "id": 1637,
    "question": "llamé",
    "questionDetails": "Le llamé para decírselo.",
    "answer": "called, phoned, paged",
    "answerDetails": "I called to tell him."
  },
  {
    "id": 1638,
    "question": "violencia",
    "questionDetails": "La protesta irrumpió con violencia mientras llegaba la policía para controlar la multitud.",
    "answer": "violence",
    "answerDetails": "The protest erupted in violence as the police arrived to control the crowd."
  },
  {
    "id": 1639,
    "question": "fuerzas",
    "questionDetails": "Tenemos que retirar nuestras fuerzas antes del siguiente plazo.",
    "answer": "forces, strength",
    "answerDetails": "We have to withdraw our forces before the next deadline."
  },
  {
    "id": 1640,
    "question": "detalle",
    "questionDetails": "El detalle de seguridad del gobernador.",
    "answer": "detail",
    "answerDetails": "The governor’s security detail."
  },
  {
    "id": 1641,
    "question": "enseñar",
    "questionDetails": "Puedes enseñar en la televisión.",
    "answer": "teach",
    "answerDetails": "You can teach on television."
  },
  {
    "id": 1642,
    "question": "pareces",
    "questionDetails": "Te pareces a mamá.",
    "answer": "seem, look",
    "answerDetails": "You seem on mother."
  },
  {
    "id": 1643,
    "question": "limpio",
    "questionDetails": "Mira qué limpio mantienes el bar.",
    "answer": "clean",
    "answerDetails": "Look how clean you keep your bar."
  },
  {
    "id": 1644,
    "question": "hará",
    "questionDetails": "Esta es una computadora muy buena. Hará que tu trabajo sea mucho más fácil.",
    "answer": "it will make, you will make",
    "answerDetails": "This is a really nice computer. It will make your work much easier."
  },
  {
    "id": 1645,
    "question": "social",
    "questionDetails": "El domicilio social de la sociedad anónima se encuentra en Dover, Delaware.",
    "answer": "registered",
    "answerDetails": "The corporation’s registered office is in Dover, Delaware."
  },
  {
    "id": 1646,
    "question": "pecho",
    "questionDetails": "Mi madre me dijo que llevara un vestido más recatado que me cubriera el pecho.",
    "answer": "bosom",
    "answerDetails": "My mother told me to wear a more modest dress that would cover my bosoms."
  },
  {
    "id": 1647,
    "question": "juega",
    "questionDetails": "Él juega en el mismo equipo de fútbol que yo.",
    "answer": "he plays",
    "answerDetails": "He plays on the same soccer team as me."
  },
  {
    "id": 1648,
    "question": "miles",
    "questionDetails": "Hemos usado miles de ellos en estos modelos.",
    "answer": "thousands, billions",
    "answerDetails": "We use thousands of them in these models."
  },
  {
    "id": 1649,
    "question": "hacían",
    "questionDetails": "Sus cascos no hacían ruido sobre el musgo.",
    "answer": "made",
    "answerDetails": "His hooves made no sound on the moss."
  },
  {
    "id": 1650,
    "question": "méxico",
    "answer": "Mexico"
  },
  {
    "id": 1651,
    "question": "reina",
    "questionDetails": "La princesa espera convertirse algún día en reina.",
    "answer": "queen, princess",
    "answerDetails": "The princess hopes to one day become a queen."
  },
  {
    "id": 1652,
    "question": "enterar",
    "questionDetails": "Nadie se tiene que enterar.",
    "answer": "know",
    "answerDetails": "Nobody has to know."
  },
  {
    "id": 1653,
    "question": "servir",
    "questionDetails": "Nunca es fácil servir a 2 maestros.",
    "answer": "serve, pour",
    "answerDetails": "It is never easy to serve two masters."
  },
  {
    "id": 1654,
    "question": "vuelo",
    "questionDetails": "Está a 2 horas de vuelo desde Edimburgo.",
    "answer": "flight, flying",
    "answerDetails": "It’s two hours’ flight from Edinburgh."
  },
  {
    "id": 1655,
    "question": "personalmente",
    "questionDetails": "Nada había ido bien personalmente o políticamente.",
    "answer": "personally",
    "answerDetails": "Nothing had gone well personally or politically."
  },
  {
    "id": 1656,
    "question": "pelea",
    "questionDetails": "El paciente ingresó en el hospital con un hombro dislocado a consecuencia de una pelea.",
    "answer": "brawl, quarrel, tussle",
    "answerDetails": "The patient came into the hospital with a dislocated shoulder that he got during a brawl."
  },
  {
    "id": 1657,
    "question": "supe",
    "questionDetails": "En el momento que la vi, supe que nos traería problemas.",
    "answer": "i knew",
    "answerDetails": "The moment I saw her, I knew she would cause us trouble."
  },
  {
    "id": 1658,
    "question": "ayudarme",
    "questionDetails": "Si quieres ayudarme, mejora mi suero.",
    "answer": "help",
    "answerDetails": "You want to help, make me a better serum."
  },
  {
    "id": 1659,
    "question": "víctima",
    "questionDetails": "La víctima de un engaño.",
    "answer": "victim",
    "answerDetails": "The victim of a hoax."
  },
  {
    "id": 1660,
    "question": "tomé",
    "questionDetails": "Yo tomé esa foto.",
    "answer": "took, tome, drank",
    "answerDetails": "I took that picture."
  },
  {
    "id": 1661,
    "question": "corte",
    "questionDetails": "Vivió durante 4 años en la corte del Rey Felipe.",
    "answer": "court, cut, outage",
    "answerDetails": "He lived for four years at the court of King Philip."
  },
  {
    "id": 1662,
    "question": "respira",
    "questionDetails": "Vamos, respira para mi.",
    "answer": "breathe, breath",
    "answerDetails": "Come on, breathe for me."
  },
  {
    "id": 1663,
    "question": "motivo",
    "questionDetails": "Dame un motivo para que me quede.",
    "answer": "reason, ground, occasion",
    "answerDetails": "Give me a reason to stay."
  },
  {
    "id": 1664,
    "question": "lío",
    "questionDetails": "Rita se metió en un lío en el trabajo y tiene miedo que la despidan.",
    "answer": "jam, mess, muddle",
    "answerDetails": "Rita got herself into a bit of a jam at work and is worried she’ll lose her job."
  },
  {
    "id": 1665,
    "question": "suelta",
    "answer": "let go"
  },
  {
    "id": 1666,
    "question": "calles",
    "questionDetails": "Las calles, no la gente.",
    "answer": "streets, blocks, roads",
    "answerDetails": "The streets, not the people."
  },
  {
    "id": 1667,
    "question": "brazo",
    "questionDetails": "Apoyó los codos en los brazos de la silla.",
    "answer": "arm, boom",
    "answerDetails": "She leaned her elbows on the arms of the chair."
  },
  {
    "id": 1668,
    "question": "mostrar",
    "questionDetails": "Los músculos de sus mandíbulas mostraron blanco a través de la piel.",
    "answer": "show, display",
    "answerDetails": "The muscles of her jaws showed white through the skin."
  },
  {
    "id": 1669,
    "question": "decimos",
    "questionDetails": "Somos los caballeros que decimos.",
    "answer": "say, tenths",
    "answerDetails": "We are the knights who say."
  },
  {
    "id": 1670,
    "question": "resultado",
    "questionDetails": "Es el resultado de la votación que cuenta.",
    "answer": "outcome",
    "answerDetails": "It is the outcome of the vote that counts."
  },
  {
    "id": 1671,
    "question": "abierta",
    "questionDetails": "La pregunta abierta es con quién.",
    "answer": "open, unlocked, openly",
    "answerDetails": "The open question is with whom."
  },
  {
    "id": 1672,
    "question": "caminando",
    "questionDetails": "El paciente refiere que se lesionó la rodilla caminando.",
    "answer": "while walking, by walking",
    "answerDetails": "The patient states that she injured her knee while walking."
  },
  {
    "id": 1673,
    "question": "corto",
    "questionDetails": "Un corto tramo de pasos.",
    "answer": "short",
    "answerDetails": "A short flight of steps."
  },
  {
    "id": 1674,
    "question": "kilómetros",
    "questionDetails": "Este océano de kilómetros de agua profundas.",
    "answer": "kilometers, km, miles",
    "answerDetails": "This ocean of liquid water kilometers deep."
  },
  {
    "id": 1675,
    "question": "paciencia",
    "questionDetails": "La paciencia es clave para superar cualquier dificultad.",
    "answer": "patience, forbearance",
    "answerDetails": "Patience is key to overcoming any difficulty."
  },
  {
    "id": 1676,
    "question": "pelear",
    "answer": "feud"
  },
  {
    "id": 1677,
    "question": "contrato",
    "questionDetails": "Firmamos un contrato para comenzar con la construcción el lunes.",
    "answer": "agreement",
    "answerDetails": "We signed an agreement to begin construction on Monday."
  },
  {
    "id": 1678,
    "question": "pura",
    "questionDetails": "Pura esencia de vida.",
    "answer": "pure, sheer, purely",
    "answerDetails": "Pure essence of life."
  },
  {
    "id": 1679,
    "question": "justamente",
    "questionDetails": "Mariano se paró y expresó justamente lo que todo estábamos pensando.",
    "answer": "precisely, justly",
    "answerDetails": "Mariano stood up and expressed precisely what everybody was thinking."
  },
  {
    "id": 1680,
    "question": "estuviste",
    "questionDetails": "¿Estuviste en casa aquí todo el día o saliste?-Estuve aquí.",
    "answer": "were you",
    "answerDetails": "Were you here all day or did you go out?-I was here."
  },
  {
    "id": 1681,
    "question": "demostrar",
    "questionDetails": "Tiene que demostrar que no se encontraba allí cuando se cometió el crimen.",
    "answer": "prove, establish",
    "answerDetails": "He has to prove that he was not there at the time the crime was committed."
  },
  {
    "id": 1682,
    "question": "objetivo",
    "questionDetails": "Examine con el objetivo de alta potencia.",
    "answer": "objective, goal, aim",
    "answerDetails": "Examine with high power objective."
  },
  {
    "id": 1683,
    "question": "alegro",
    "questionDetails": "Yo también me alegro de verte.",
    "answer": "am glad, am pleased, glad",
    "answerDetails": "I too am glad to see you."
  },
  {
    "id": 1684,
    "question": "fueras",
    "questionDetails": "Fue como si fueras alguien más.",
    "answer": "were",
    "answerDetails": "It was like you were someone else."
  },
  {
    "id": 1685,
    "question": "privado",
    "questionDetails": "Creo que deberíamos discutirlo en privado.",
    "answer": "private",
    "answerDetails": "I think we should discuss this in private."
  },
  {
    "id": 1686,
    "question": "puntos",
    "questionDetails": "Pierdes tus tres puntos.",
    "answer": "points, dots, spots",
    "answerDetails": "You lose three points."
  },
  {
    "id": 1687,
    "question": "disfrutar",
    "questionDetails": "Con dinero, podríamos disfrutar de buenas comidas.",
    "answer": "enjoy",
    "answerDetails": "With money, we should enjoy good meals."
  },
  {
    "id": 1688,
    "question": "reconocer",
    "questionDetails": "El Dr. Friedman está programando su computadora para reconocer las formas de los trazos en las manos de varios escritores.",
    "answer": "recognize",
    "answerDetails": "Dr Friedman is programming his computer to recognize the shapes of strokes in the hands of various writers."
  },
  {
    "id": 1689,
    "question": "altura",
    "questionDetails": "La altura del nuevo edificio es impresionante.",
    "answer": "height",
    "answerDetails": "The height of the new building is impressive."
  },
  {
    "id": 1690,
    "question": "orgullo",
    "questionDetails": "El orgullo del pueblo es la piscina.",
    "answer": "pride",
    "answerDetails": "The pride of the village is the swimming pool."
  },
  {
    "id": 1691,
    "question": "debía",
    "questionDetails": "Dijo que le debía un favor.",
    "answer": "owed, should",
    "answerDetails": "He said you owed him one."
  },
  {
    "id": 1692,
    "question": "hablaba",
    "answer": "he talked"
  },
  {
    "id": 1693,
    "question": "doña",
    "answer": "donut"
  },
  {
    "id": 1694,
    "question": "celular",
    "questionDetails": "Tu celular pitó; se está quedando sin batería.",
    "answer": "mobile",
    "answerDetails": "Your mobile just beeped. It’s running out of juice."
  },
  {
    "id": 1695,
    "question": "niñas",
    "questionDetails": "Unas Niñas llegaron a la casa buscando a Rebecca para salir a Jugar.",
    "answer": "some girls",
    "answerDetails": "Some girls came to the house looking for Rebecca to go out and play."
  },
  {
    "id": 1696,
    "question": "pendiente",
    "questionDetails": "9 casos seguían pendientes.",
    "answer": "pending, slope, outstanding",
    "answerDetails": "9 cases were still pending."
  },
  {
    "id": 1697,
    "question": "suéltame",
    "answer": "Let me"
  },
  {
    "id": 1698,
    "question": "aceptar",
    "questionDetails": "Máquinas expendedoras que aceptaron 100 monedas de yen para latas de cerveza.",
    "answer": "accept",
    "answerDetails": "Vending machines that accepted 100-yen coins for cans of beer."
  },
  {
    "id": 1699,
    "question": "viniste",
    "questionDetails": "Bienvenido, me alegra que viniste. ¡ Entra!.",
    "answer": "you came",
    "answerDetails": "Welcome, I’m glad you came. Come on in!."
  },
  {
    "id": 1700,
    "question": "auto",
    "questionDetails": "Tengo un mapa, pero no en el auto.",
    "answer": "car",
    "answerDetails": "I have a map, but not in the car."
  }
]